https://www.mark-knopfler-news.co.uk/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
We take the privacy of our Website visitors very seriously. We ask that you read this Privacy Policy (Policy) carefully as it contains important information about how we will use your personal data.
For the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation and all other relevant legislation, Mark Knopfler News (‘we’ or ‘us’) is the ‘data controller’ which is responsible for, and controls the processing of, your personal data.
Personal data we may collect about you
Information that you provide
Personal information about you (such as your name and email address) will be obtained, whenever you complete forms on the Website.
We will also obtain personal information you provide when you send us feedback, post material, contact us for any reason and by any medium, sign up to a service, share information via the Website’s social media functions, enter a competition, or report a problem with the Website.
We may retain a record of any contact you make with us.
Personal information about other individuals
If you give us information on behalf of someone else, you confirm that the other person has appointed you to act on his/her behalf and has agreed that you can:
give consent on his/her behalf to the processing of his/her data;
give consent to any transfer of his/her data;
Information from third parties
Information that we will collect automatically:
Cookies: We may monitor your use of the Website through the use of cookies and similar tracking devices. For example, we may monitor how many times you use the Website, which pages you go to and traffic data. This information helps us to build a profile of our users. Some of this data will be aggregated or statistical, which means that we will not be able to identify you individually. For further information on our use of cookies, please see the sections on cookies below.
Device information: We may also collect information about your device each time you use the Website. For example, we may collect information on the type of mobile device that you are using, the MAC address of the device’s wireless network interface, the type of mobile browser that you are using, the mobile operating system that you are using, mobile network information and the time zone setting.
How we use your personal data
We use your personal data for the following purposes:
administration;
research, statistical analysis and behavioural analysis;
marketing – see ‘Marketing’, below;
fraud prevention and detection;
to notify you of any changes to the Website or to our services that may affect you;
improving our services.
What is our lawful basis or ground for using your personal data?
Under laws that are designed to protect your personal data, we need to have what is called a lawful basis or ground each time we use, share or otherwise process your personal data.
Where possible we always endeavor to process data with fully informed consent. Where you give your consent for us to process your personal information, we shall do so on the terms of this Privacy Policy.
We may also need to process your personal data to comply with any legal obligations which may be applicable. Likewise, we may process your personal data where this is in the public interest or it is to protect your vital interests, but this will only be in rare circumstances.
In most cases, our processing of your personal data is necessary for the performance of our services to you.
Certain uses of your personal data, or other processing activities, may not be strictly necessary to perform our services to you, however, they may be necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interests or the legitimate interests of a third party. They may also be in your interests.
When we say “legitimate interests”, we mean our (or a third party’s) interests in enabling us to provide our services to you as efficiently and securely as possible. For example, we may choose to use a third party to store your personal data; we may do this in part because our use of that service means that your personal data is more secure.
Marketing
The Website may contain links to other websites or apps which we or our partners own, or websites or apps of our partners or third parties. Please note that if you follow any of these links, the websites, apps and services provided through them will have their own privacy policies/terms of use. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for their respective privacy policies/terms of use or the collection and use of any personal data collected through these websites, apps or services. Please ensure that you review the relevant privacy policies/terms of use prior to providing any personal data to, or using these websites, apps and services.
Disclosure of your personal data
We may disclose your personal data to:
a third party who acquires Mark Knopfler News or acquires substantially all of its assets, in which case the personal data shall be one of the acquired assets;
law enforcement and regulatory agencies in connection with any investigation to help prevent unlawful activity or as otherwise required by applicable law.
Keeping your data secure
We will use technical and organisational measures to safeguard your personal data, for example:
we store your personal data on secure servers;
entered details are encrypted using SSL technology.
While we will use all reasonable efforts to safeguard your personal data, you acknowledge that the use of the internet is not entirely secure and for this reason we cannot guarantee the security or integrity of any personal data that are transferred from you or to you via the internet.
Transfers of data out of the EEA
We will make reasonable efforts to ensure that your data is not transferred outside the European Economic Area (EEA). Where we use data servers that may transfer data out of the EEA we will take steps to ensure adequate protections are in place to ensure the security of your information and give you remedies in the unlikely event of a security breach.
All information you provide to us is stored with secure data processors.
Monitoring
We may monitor and record communications with you (such as emails) for the purpose of quality assurance, fraud prevention and compliance.
Your rights
We will collect and store information about you as detailed above.
You can remove or amend your consent at any time by emailing admin@mark-knopfler-news.co.uk, or by using the unsubscribe facility in the mailing list feature.
These rights may not apply in all situations or in relation to all types of processing.
How long we will store your data
We will store your data for as long as necessary for the purpose of processing. The data may be deleted in the following circumstances:
You have withdrawn your consent to data processing
The original purpose for processing the data is no longer relevant or cannot be performed any more.
The data is no longer up to date or accurate
Children
Mark Knopfler News only offers services to individuals over the age of 16. In using our services, you confirm that you have read and consented to this Policy and verify that you are over the age of 16.
Use of cookies
A cookie is a small text file which is placed onto your mobile (or other electronic device) when you access our Website. We use cookies and other online tracking devices on our Website to:
recognise you whenever you visit the Website (this speeds up your access to the Website as you do not have to log on each time);
obtain information about your preferences, online movements and use of the internet;
carry out research and statistical analysis to help improve our content, products and services and to help us better understand our visitor and customer requirements and interests;
make your online experience more efficient and enjoyable.
The information we obtain from our use of cookies will not usually contain your personal data. Although we may obtain information about your device such as your IP address, your browser and/or other internet log information, this will not usually identify you personally. In certain circumstances we may collect personal information about you—but only where you voluntarily provide it (e.g. by completing an online form).
In most cases we will need your consent in order to use cookies on this Website. The exception is where the cookie is essential in order for us to provide you with a service you have requested.
Consent (browser settings)
If you visit our Website when your browser is set to accept cookies, we will interpret this as an indication that you consent to our use of cookies and other similar technologies as described in this Website’s cookie policy. If you change your mind in the future about letting us use cookies, you can modify the settings of your browser to reject cookies or disable cookies completely.
Consent (notification on site load)
There is a notice upon loading up the Website at the bottom of the page which advises you that cookies are being used, and by clicking the button will confirm this acknowledgement. If you use this Website after this notification has been displayed to you, we will assume that you consent to our use of cookies for the purposes described in this Website’s Privacy Policy.
Third party cookies
We work with third-party suppliers who may also set cookies on our Website, for example Google, Facebook, Twitter, and YouTube which we may use to display video content. These third-party suppliers are responsible for the cookies they set on our site. If you want further information please go to the website for the relevant third party. You will find additional information in the table below.
Description of cookies
The table below is designed to provide more information about the cookies we use and why:
Name of cookie
_ga
Owner
Google Inc.
Purpose of cookie
Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.
Duration
2 years
_gat
Owner
Google Inc.
Purpose of cookie
Used by Google Analytics to throttle request rate.
Duration
Session
_gid
Owner
Google Inc.
Purpose of cookie
Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.
Duration
Session
collect
Owner
Google Inc.
Purpose of cookie
Used to send data to Google Analytics about the visitor’s device and behaviour. Tracks the visitor across devices and marketing channels.
Duration
Session
_hjIncludedInSample
Owner
HotJar
Purpose of cookie
Determines if the user’s navigation should be registered in a certain statistical placeholder.
Duration
Session
PREF
Owner
YouTube
Purpose of cookie
Registers a unique ID that is used by Google to keep statistics of how the visitor uses YouTube videos across different websites.
Duration
8 months
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE
Owner
YouTube
Purpose of cookie
Tries to estimate the users’ bandwidth on pages with integrated YouTube videos.
Duration
179 days
YSC
Owner
YouTube
Purpose of cookie
Registers a unique ID to keep statistics of what videos from YouTube the user has seen .
Duration
Session
Name of cookie
Owner
Purpose of cookie
Duration
_ga
Google Inc.
Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.
2 years
_gat
Google Inc.
Used by Google Analytics to throttle request rate.
Session
_gid
Google Inc.
Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.
Session
collect
Google Inc.
Used to send data to Google Analytics about the visitor’s device and behaviour. Tracks the visitor across devices and marketing channels.
Session
_hjIncludedInSample
HotJar
Determines if the user’s navigation should be registered in a certain statistical placeholder.
Session
PREF
YouTube
Registers a unique ID that is used by Google to keep statistics of how the visitor uses YouTube videos across different websites.
8 months
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE
YouTube
Tries to estimate the users’ bandwidth on pages with integrated YouTube videos.
179 days
YSC
YouTube
Registers a unique ID to keep statistics of what videos from YouTube the user has seen .
Session
How to turn off cookies
If you do not want to accept cookies, you can change your browser settings so that cookies are not accepted. If you do this, please be aware that you may lose some of the functionality of the Website. For further information about cookies and how to disable them please go to: www.aboutcookies.org
Our contact details
If you wish to contact us, please send us an email at admin@mark-knopfler-news.co.uk
Changes to this Privacy Policy
We may change this Policy from time to time. You should check this policy frequently to ensure you are aware of the most recent version that will apply each time you use the Website.
Data Protection Supervisory Authority
The Data Protection Supervisory Authority in the UK is the Information Commissioner’s Office. Should you have any complaints about the way we handle your data, you may direct them to the ICO. More information on the ICO can be found on their website here: https://ico.org.uk
FollowFollow
Material published on this web site is subject to copyright and all rights are reserved.
© Mark Knopfler News 2020
Website by Lean Mean Digital Ltd
Privacy Policy
Material published on this web site is subject to copyright and all rights are reserved.
© Mark Knopfler News 2020
Website by Lean Mean Digital Ltd
Privacy Policy
